- This
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): fall during hunting season, I was getting a slice of pizza at a general store in a small town in the mountains of Western Maine. And I was standing in line and I ran into a guy I know, a guy I like a lot called Esau Cooper, who was a local excavator. And he said,
Speaker 2: "I've been watching
you, interviewing
Speaker 3: all these people, why don't you interview me? I got interesting stuff to say." And I thought, "You know, I bet he does."
Speaker 3: Esau Cooper is an interesting person.
Speaker 4: Esau Cooper is not only
a
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): good upstanding citizen of his town, to remain unnamed, in the Western Maine Mountains, but he's also the local lawnmower racing champ. Every year, this town in August has a lawnmower race, and Esau Cooper often wins it, sometimes at great personal risk.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Here's a video of it you saw as the one in the
Speaker 5: green John Deere that runs into the camera.
Lawn Mower
Speaker 6: Racing Lawn Mower Racing is one of those things you make fun of As a curiosity, an oddity for rural areas,
Speaker 6: is until you
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): see it and then you realize these guys are legit automotive engineers and they have major stones. It's dangerous. That video, by the way, is shot by Toby Wenzel.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Esau Cooper, the man on the green John Deere, joins us now in studio. Esau, it's great to see you.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Good to be here. I wasn't joking.
First
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Alunmoor racing, how fast do those go? The sky's the limit. It depends on how
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): fast you make it go. Our particular track in Andover,
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): 25 30 miles an hour is probably too fast to make turn one so not particularly
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): fast but because the track's small and tight it looks like you're flying you know it certainly does i've seen
it the
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): straight stretch is only 100
feet long
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): so if you get attracted a pull
for
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): 100 feet yeah
you're good
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): well so how do you get a ride-on mower to go 30 miles an hour change the pulleys and get rid of the
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): governor how
do you get rid of
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): the governor
you
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): just unhook a few springs and pull it back
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): and so the the motor turns pushes as fast as it can all the time it's it's not good for longevity of the motor
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): but
yeah yeah
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): could you do that in any vehicle
Speaker 14: you can get
rid of
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): the governor on a lawnmower
engine yeah
Speaker 14: wow so you do that over the where
oh no
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): winter i log snowmobile
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): hunt all
right
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): - Well, it's springtime when there's no, you can't cut wood and it's too early to start digging. That's when the lawnmowers come out and we start tinkering
Speaker 17: them up. - For people who don't live in an area where logging's big, why can't you log in the spring?
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): - It's a mud season. They post the roads. So you can't drive big trucks on the roads and the snow melts and the ground gets really soft. The frost goes out and it's just the ground is soft. You can't do much other than go in the garage and fix equipment.
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): tinker on lawnmowers and how long have you been
Speaker 17: logging uh 30 years a guy from your
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): town got killed last year logging good friend of mine
yep um how'd that
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): happen and how do people get killed logging
well generally
Speaker 18: speaking people get complacent
Speaker 19: yeah um he was actually taught
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): logging and um he knew how to do
it was
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): considered a considerable logger
Uh, I
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): looked at
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): the site. Yeah. He, uh,
he went and cut
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): another tree while, while a tree got, a tree got hung up. Yeah. And
he
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): went and cut another tree in the line of sight of that tree that was hung up and the tree fell. Yeah. On him and killed
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): him. So he was, I mean, by reputation was, and you just said like knew exactly what he was doing. Yeah.
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): do you ever worry about getting hurt logging yeah
yeah yeah
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): yeah you just
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): i mean especially after that um you just you don't take those chances yeah but this is all you know everybody everybody takes
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): chances now
and then
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): you know
so
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): how did you end up living
in a
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): little town in western maine
oh
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): well
My mom
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): is from Livermore Falls area. She grew up in Maine. My dad was from all over the Northeast. I was born in New London, Connecticut. We
moved to
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): a little trailer park in Peru when I was really young. Peru, Maine. Yes. And then we moved to another small town in Western Maine. What town? Rumford Center. Yep. Very small town. Yep.
and
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): when i was 10 years my father died when i was six and shortly thereafter um my mom got remarried and we moved to andover when i was 10 and i was disgusted i actually ran away from home
where'd you
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): go an old girl scout camp on the whippoor road me and a buddy of mine uh i ran away on my 10 speed and disappeared for a day or two until they finally found us you know and
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): we were just at that time we were into rambo yeah you know outdoor survivalists and stuff so we were gonna i don't know what we're thinking i just was making a statement i guess that i this town sucks i'm from rumpet and i'm going back to rumpet
yeah
Speaker 22: you thought andover was bad
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): i was it was it was not you know i didn't know anybody shortly thereafter though i found i met two guys that uh you know i consider brothers now one of them's
Speaker 23 (lower-pitched voice): one of them's gone to heaven but the other one i consider a brother you know it
Man 24: was it was the three of us me mike and mike and we grew up together and uh one of the mikes died when i was 19. oof died in a car accident yeah
yeah so yeah
Man 24: that changes
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): you yeah it does yeah did you stay in the town yep i did uh until i was 25. where'd
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): you go
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): traveled all over the country putting in natural gas pipelines really yeah running from myself
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): what do you mean well i was uh yeah you know i i played too hard you know work hard and drink even harder on the weekends and yeah
um each town i
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): there were temporary jobs you go into a
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): Going to a town, I'd say, it's going to be different this time, you
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): know? And it was never any different. Just the partying? Yeah, the partying, and it progressed. I started just drinking,
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): and then got into drugs, and just, you know, it was a time in my life when at one
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): time I was going to make a career of pipelining. And then at 31, I sobered up, and I tried to keep pipelining, and I realized that it's
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): just...
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): When I quit drinking, I had to let things go. How did you sober up? Well, they
first tried
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): to put me in rehab at 13, and I wouldn't go. 13 years old? Yes, yes. They wouldn't take me up to Bangor because the doctor says, the doctor's
talking
Speaker 26: to me, so I don't got a problem with alcohol. I love alcohol. At
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): that time, it was just...
I was
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): just drinking at
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): that time, I believe. Yeah. And then at 15, I went in and I spent three, four days in detox because I ate too many Valiums. Yeah. And ended up in rehab for a month. It's
a
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): 28-day program. On the 21st day, I got kicked out. For what?
Well, I had
Speaker 29: been
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): reprimanded for...
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): something I don't remember what but one of the ways they punished you was at that time you could smoke right in rehab you know
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): and no cigarettes for you so I was like yeah okay and so I got
in the
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): line to get my daily cigarette or whatever it was a long time ago and got up the line got the cigarette
went back to
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): the smoking area I had a lighter I was just about to light
it
And the
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): nurse realized that I wasn't supposed to have a cigarette. So she bolted
over to me and
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): took my cigarette and said,
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): you can't have that. You're being punished. I said, oh, really? And she's walking away. I said, take your effing lighter too. And I threw it at her. And had I hit her
with that
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): lighter, I
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): would have had to go to
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): NYC, Maine Youth Center. Oh, I missed. Thank God. And they booted me.
Speaker 23 (lower-pitched voice): That was the end of that.
Speaker 32: damn yeah
did
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): you go to rehab again after that uh
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): 10 years later yeah 25 and i checked myself in i had a massive cocaine problem and all i really
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): wanted to do was quit that yeah so when i got out of there i stayed sober for a little while of course started back and that's when i started
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): pipeline yeah i actually got hired i got hired
in uh
the
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): paper mill in Rumford while I was in rehab.
And I told them, I
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): said, well, I'm in rehab right now because I had passed all their testing and they wanted me and they
called me up and
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): said, okay, let's come to work. I said, well, small problem, I'm in rehab right now. Oh, that's okay when you get out, come on. So I did, I went to work from where I lasted 10 days and quit. Why? I went back log and I couldn't stand it. Yeah. It was inside,
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): it was toxic. Yeah. All my coworkers were...
I'm
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): overweight and bald and unhappy.
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. Do you think it makes you bald working on a paper mill? I
Speaker 35: don't know about that. I probably, yeah, that was probably mean, but it just didn't look happy.
Speaker 36 (lower-pitched voice): No, I agree. I was an outdoor enthusiast, you
know, and I
Speaker 36 (lower-pitched voice): just,
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): so I left, you know, I left and went back logging and shortly thereafter I jumped on, they were laying a natural gas pipeline in Peru. Yeah.
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): And I got hired on that, and that
was
Speaker 36 (lower-pitched voice): a godsend. The wages were high, the outdoor, it was grueling. It was hard work, and the mud, and
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): equipment, and laying pipe across, like, how are we gonna lay a pipe across that? You know, it was- - Like a grand ledge or something. - Swamp, yeah, river crossings, just unreal stuff. Tying
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): crews, you know, is where all the prestigious on a pipeline, a tying crew.
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): and the other ones who connect the pipes
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): connect the pipes in the hard spots mainline lays it in the easy spots and the tying
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): crews come in and connect the pipe in all the difficult areas the swamps yeah so yeah i got on that and started working that and it was it was my thing i loved it i was going to make a career out of it yeah and uh
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): i did it for seven years until i realized it was killing me you know
not
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): so much the work but the the nightlife because with pipeline and in a different town every six months came
bar life
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): yeah
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): living in a motel and lots of drugs and do all the guys go out together at night not all of them not all of them no there's there was sober good hard
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): working normal people yeah
and
But
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): you know, I wasn't one of them. I
was a
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): party animal and they liked that, you know what I mean? They liked you to work hard and play even harder.
- Well,
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): when you're working
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): hard, you can party hard for a while. How did you
end up stopping? It sounds like
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): you've been trying to stop for like
a
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): long time. - I knew,
I don't
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): know.
I
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): left South Chicago on a job, and I headed east to another job. I
quit one
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): job, was headed to another. I wanted to make a change. And when I got
to the East
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): Coast, it was either head south to that job or head home and try to straighten my ass out. And I was in trouble. I knew
I
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): was afraid my mom was going to go to my funeral. Wow. It was really in my mind, you know.
And at
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): that time, I didn't know I had a heart condition. But
you could just
Speaker 41: feel there was something wrong? Yeah.
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): I was
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): living hard, doing a lot of drugs, snorting a lot of cocaine, putting chunks of, you know, gram chunks of cocaine in my coffee in the morning. Does that work? Before I
went to work. Party all
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): night, smoke crack all
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): night long, sleep for 10 minutes, go to work six days a week, sometimes seven. Wow. It was intense. It sounds intense. I made a ton of money.
At the end
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): of it, I had my room would be paid. My truck would be paid. I'd had top hours of work and foreman. Yeah. And they just throw money at you, and you try real hard. And I just, I didn't want to die. I didn't want my mom going to my funeral because
I knew it
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): would kill her. So you've been to rehab three times at this point. Did you quit in rehab a fourth time? No. Really?
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): No. By this time, I had...
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): been taught enough i knew where the help was it was a 12-step program
that i had been
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): to before yeah one monday morning i woke up and things were different i don't know to this day i don't know what happened but things just were different i knew i was in trouble um and
instead of going to
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): the store and buying beer
Because
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): that's what I wanted to do that morning. I woke up on my stepfather's couch. I was living at the time on my stepdad's
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): couch.
I had a
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): pickup, and that's it. I didn't have a pot to piss in or
a window
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): to throw it out. Yeah.
So I just
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): went to a meeting. I went to a meeting that Monday night, and I've been sober ever since. That's amazing. How long has it been? It'll be 20
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): years in March. Wow. Wow.
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): how have you been able to stay sober all that time god yeah he
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): yeah i i made a decision
you know
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): shortly after that i met a gentleman
um he's deceased now his
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): name was kip cummings and
he became
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): my sponsor and
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): he saved my life
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): i could relate to him he was a grumpy old man yeah and he was black and white if you do this you get that result and i responded
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): to that he'd say there are clear-cut directions in this book and you'll get this result and i've always been able to read
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): directions and do something yes that's how my mind works yeah um and it made sense to me and he reminded
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): me of like my grandfather or my father yeah i kind of you know i like old
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): mean old men who are you know you can tell they've worked hard yeah and they've been through the ringer and i could relate to them yeah i've always been around people like that so
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): he helped me he just taught me how to become a man how
to stay
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): sober and and he
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): he's he died a few years back but he
he he just
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): taught me how to be a
Speaker 14: grown-up was he right i mean did your life change for the better once you got sober
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): Well, it slowly has. I'm
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): in the process of changing my life. It's been a long journey. Yeah. I quit
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): drinking, doing drugs. I was straight up for a year and a half.
And not
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): everybody knows this. But I couldn't
Speaker 42 (lower-pitched voice): take the pressure of life. I started smoking pot. Yeah.
So it took me a
Speaker 42 (lower-pitched voice): long time.
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): I, I didn't want to be,
I felt
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): like a hypocrite trying to help people to get sober, you know,
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): talk at a meeting and then get high on the ride home. Yeah. So I had a lot of hypocritical feelings up towards myself, but, uh, March 13th, 2021, I was able to
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): kick that.
What do
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): you...
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): So shortly after they legalized
Speaker 43: it, I
Speaker 44: was about to say it's legal in your state. Yeah. What are
Speaker 43: your worst idea ever? I voted no. Why? It's
just not
Speaker 43: sending a good
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): message. Yeah, it's just not. It's it's do we want to promote drugs? Do we really want
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): to or do we want to just. I
don't I don't know
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): what the answer is. I
don't want to chase around a
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): bunch of potheads and spend a bunch of money.
on
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): it yeah i also
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): don't want to just have it be okay and be i mean maybe you
Speaker 45: know the tobacco campaigns that they have
Speaker 46: yeah why don't we have weed campaigns telling you will you tell me i mean you've used a lot of drugs you smoked a lot of weed in your life yeah why do you clearly made me dumber it put me in a little bubble so i couldn't relate
Speaker 35: with people
Speaker 46: yeah
Instead of
Speaker 42 (lower-pitched voice): relying on my higher power, God, Jesus Christ, I
relied on
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): marijuana. And before that it was alcohol, before that it was cocaine, you know, all this stuff. My higher power now is God.
God, the
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): God, you know.
That has
Speaker 47: evolved. It started out
as...
i i wasn't a
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): godly person when i quit drinking yeah but i learned through a
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): 12-step program and eventually through the bible that that is the answer to all our problems i believe in my yes yes i agree so
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): as someone
who smoked a
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): lot of marijuana you think it is bad for people yes i do
that's
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): an
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): unpopular thing to say yeah why because people don't want to hear it
yeah they
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): don't want to hear they don't want to hear it um i have a lot of successful friends
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): that smoke daily yeah so it's you can't if you don't ever see the insanity it's like cigarettes yeah where's the insanity it's easy to see how bad alcohol is for you yeah or cocaine or crack or heroin but marijuana is so insidious
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): It's so mild, it's
hard
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): to see how it's holding you back. I mean, myself
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): personally,
I became a better
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): businessman, a better parent. I can remember numbers now. You know, I can, it's just better. I'm not in that bubble. I can relate to people. I can relate.
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): I can see
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): people in mills market and start up a conversation with them instead of running out the door because I smell like a skunk. Yeah. You know?
Speaker 29: Where did you get your politics
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): from?
I'd say my
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Uncle Esau. Your Uncle Esau. My Uncle Esau. I think that's a song, isn't it? I don't know. I don't know.
You
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): know, it's funny. I have never met another Esau except for people in my family.
And
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): then just the other day, I was listening to a podcast on the radio, and there was this dude named Esau, a
black guy
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): named Esau who was a pastor, and he's in, like,
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): Massachusetts.
And I
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): was listening to Bible-thumping radio, and this dude was on there. His name was Esau, and I was
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): like, wow, that was amazing. The first time ever. What was your Uncle Esau like? He was a staunch Republican, free market guy.
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah? Yeah. Yeah. Where was he from? Auburn. Auburn.
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): man yeah what do you do he's still he's still in
auburn
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): he's a paver
yeah
Speaker 16: yeah my whole father's side of the family were all
pavers
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): really asphalt pavers yep cooper paving
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): there's a whole bunch of them yeah bred to pave pave driveways paved roads paved
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): parking lots yep paved pay pay pay i worked for him for two years out of out of us when i first got sober i went to work for my
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): cousin
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): cooper paving llc and i lasted a couple years and had to move on
well what
Speaker 51: happened i bought an excavator to
fix
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): up a piece of land of mine and
it kind of
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): evolved and i started getting side jobs and i finally said you know what screw it i'm going on my own that's how i became
Man 24: that's how i get into the business
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): do you like it the business
i'm in
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): yeah i love what i do
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): i don't necessarily like the business aspect of it but you like excavating yeah what why i like taking raw land and creating something
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): out of it yeah you know i can stand on the side of a road and look at the contour of the land and some folks want it cleared
and they
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): want to put
a house and i
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): can see you know you
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): can see you
know how
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): it should be
and
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): you get a vision and you do it and it's awesome it's very rewarding i believe that yeah it's
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): kind of artistic
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): do you do you
notice the
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): difference between the town you grew up in which you still live in the way it was when you were a kid and it is now
other than there's a lot
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): of people i don't know now yeah
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): as far as the politics goes it's basically the same what about the country you grew
Speaker 52: up in how
is it different oh
i'm
Speaker 29: distraught about my country why because our freedoms are just being
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): taken away from us daily what
the what the federal
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): government is doing to mr trump with the like political persecution and the what
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): is it called lawfare
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): yeah yeah it's just gross it's gross I'll see
you next time.
it's
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): gross and i believe that
this is what happened
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): this country has turned
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): from god and now we're cursed in a and this is what we got that's my theory
do most
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): people you know like trump most
people i know yeah
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): yeah why is trump so popular in rural america
Because
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): they're blue-collar workers. There's
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): very few educated elites. And actually, there's a couple in our town, and they don't like Trump. Really? Yeah. So it's
a class
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): thing, as
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): far as you can tell.
Speaker 54: Yeah, yeah. I
have a
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): friend. She's a lady. She's a liberal. She's a
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): progressive. She loathes Trump.
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): and that's cool we're still friends you know i don't talk politics with her except sometimes i
just kind of
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): throw in a little jab like you know just to get her goat what do you say
oh she
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): might try being um she may she may
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): try to express
uh how do i put it
Speaker 36 (lower-pitched voice): a desire to be compassionate of the gender baloney and stuff like that. And I'll totally state where I am, you know. I
guess I
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): recent, she accused
me of being a
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): sexist and I was like, yeah, I am, I guess, a sexist. Sorry.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): What did she say? She laughed, you know, she knows me. It's all good. You sure she wasn't trying to say sexy?
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): No,
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): I don't think so, because she's
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): like 70-something. I don't think so. But
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): she's, yeah, I just think she's crazier than the shithouse rat. Yeah. And it's okay,
because there's a lot of
Speaker 58: crazy people in Andover. You know
what I
Speaker 58: mean? I weren't supposed
to use
Speaker 58: that name. What
Speaker 59: percentage of your town do you think will vote for Trump? I
don't know,
Speaker 60: 50,
Speaker 59: 60.
Speaker 61: Yeah.
Yeah.
I
Speaker 61: mean, there's a bunch of people
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): that just refuse to see the truth. I have
a, someone
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): in my
family is all, hates
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): Trump, going to vote Democratic, and he just, I'm not going to say his name, but it just, it's
Speaker 20: like, if
you go
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): principle, if you stand there and
Speaker 62: you talk on principle, okay, we believe in this, we believe in this, we believe in this, we're just the same.
But
Speaker 63: when it comes voting day, check
the
Speaker 64: Democratic box.
How do
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): you... So a lot... You live in Maine, which is run by socialists.
Oh, you don't
Speaker 65: like the
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): leadership of the state? I don't like our current Secretary of State.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): He's gone on the bad side of me with the whole trying to take Mr. Trump off the...
the
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): primary ballot
Speaker 67: but it does it seems like that's very far away from where you live like
Speaker 14: it's a totally different
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): world well not
if you
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): i watch the news yeah yeah i mean this if
you watch the
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): news i i'm kind
of a
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): news junkie i watch so where do
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): you get your news like
what
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): yeah like you i mean you live you know hours from the nearest airport so it's pretty far away right mm-hmm
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): where do you
how do
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): you find out what's going on in the world what do you read what do you watch tv yeah i uh i used
to
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): be uh i used to watch a lot of fox news yeah
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): matter of fact i watched it as often as my family would let me yeah you know
i turned fox
Speaker 68: on and my wife and my kids would be like oh here we go again you know because they just had it they don't
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): want yeah but i i listened to the news two three nights a week maybe
Speaker 69: four
So
Speaker 69: the day they fired your ass was the last day I have not watched 10 seconds
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): of Fox since they fired you. Have you caught
your wife
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): or kids watching? Nope. Just on principle. Well, thank you. Just on principle. Just because I just think it was
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): wrong.
Because it was obvious
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): that they were putting pressure. You were telling the truth. In my opinion, you were telling the truth about a bunch of stuff and you got too close to the truth.
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): and they got radio so that's just my
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): thing on that so where do you go now i go now i'm watching news max now i'm a news max
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): guy what
do you think
Speaker 71: well it's all right it's grown on me you
go
Speaker 72: on the internet
no not
Speaker 72: not for news no what's your shirt mean this
is a
Speaker 73: direct
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): retort to joe biden's speech
That
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): he gave last week where he basically called all Trump supporters domestic terrorists.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. Okay. Let's brand domestic terrorism as cool. That's
what I'm saying. Because I'm a
Speaker 42 (lower-pitched voice): Bible-thumping, hard-working, blue-collar, you know, I got a few guns. I'm no gun expert, but I got a few guns.
You
Speaker 42 (lower-pitched voice): know, I
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): hunt fish, I will die for my country. Oh, that's a good story. I tried to go into the service. Yeah. I
scored
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): like in the 99 percentile
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): of my ASVABs. I believe it. My junior year. So
my senior
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): year, and I was all advanced entry or whatever you call
it, right there in
Speaker 74: Desert Storm. So
I was all
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): enlisted my junior year. My
senior year,
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): this general... Where'd you go to high school? Telstra.
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): Yep. Bethel, Maine. Hmm.
My
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): senior year, this general comes in,
and he
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): wants to get inside my head and see what I'm good at. I'm like, yeah. So I get in the room with him, and I start being honest with the guy. I
told him what I
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): had going. I wanted to get out of here. I want to change my life. I told him I had, you
know, I was
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): partying, and, you know, I was honest with him. And at the end of that meeting, he's like, we don't want you.
No, no.
why
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): why the you know the partying the drugs the drama the you know yeah he didn't it wouldn't take me so their
loss you know
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): maybe maybe i you know maybe that was god you know maybe he
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): didn't want me to go because i might have popped yeah you know what i mean might have got in there
and
tried
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): too hard and just exploded on the thing and I wouldn't be here sitting with
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): you, talking with you,
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): embarrassing my kids and what? Wow. So you partied too hard for the U.S. Army? Yes. Yes. Yeah,
they wouldn't
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): take it. I was honest. I
didn't realize I
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): was supposed to lie. If someone would have said, don't tell the guy that you...
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): don't tell him about your personal things just say yes or no sir and no one told me i just i told him what i had going on it was my ticket to ride i'm getting out of here i'm gonna go straighten my life out and be somebody
then he's
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): like no we
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): don't want you did
you so
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): obviously you changed your view though because you did leave for a while on the pipeline but then you came back
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): yeah to your town are you happy that you did that
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): yeah well mainly because my mom she's aging yeah and i live
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): a thousand feet from her now and that's why i live in andover yeah yeah i i found a few cool
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): places in the country that i could have stayed at you know but i i basically came and lived where i lived because my mom my i have two sisters yeah one's deceased and
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): one's still with us, but they had moved away. One lived in New York,
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): one lived in Virginia. And she, you know, my mom and my stepdad were getting age, up
there in
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): the age, and I felt obligated
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): to come home and help them live out the
rest of the
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): years. Are you glad you did? Oh,
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): absolutely. Absolutely. Yeah. What do you think of the cities now?
Well, it's
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): atrocious.
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah.
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): it's atrocious i i i
don't even know what
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): to say about it they've gone so far
crazy town
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): that you know the real estate
Speaker 75: prices in our town are stupid now because everybody wants to get out of
the city yeah
Speaker 75: they're all moving up this
way
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): then you know with that's good for business but don't bring your friggin laws with you you know what i mean yeah i
don't mind
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): people i like people i actually do like people yeah but i don't like their rules and regulations
Speaker 38 (lower-pitched voice): and all that that's it creeps me out it does do you think
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): they'll bring them oh most likely
you
Speaker 76: know one
thing you can count on
Speaker 76: in life and that is going to change
yeah
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): And that liberals are going to show up and
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): wreck everything. Yep, yep. Maybe we'll have to move north. You know, maybe we'll have to.
You live pretty
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): close to Canada already. Yeah. I
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): had
a cool story about
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): Canada. What is it? I went to Canada on my 18th birthday. We went to Sherbrooke. Yep. Went to the, yeah. And had a really good time. That's all I'm going to.
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): did you wind up in jail can you go back to
Speaker 77: go but i should have gone to jail
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): but i didn't get caught hey anything related to cows or what'd you do no no no no just uh a bad parallel parking job and uh intoxicated behind the wheel nothing too serious yeah i think you can
Speaker 23 (lower-pitched voice): parallel park any way you want in canada i think is it okay to move the vehicle and take the spot not
if it's
Speaker 78: not your vehicle it's not no
Speaker 78: Yeah, it's just
been so
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): many, there's so many things that have, I
have a
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): lot of
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): lives. Not so much now, you know, but back in the day, I am lucky to be alive. Well,
now
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): though, too, though you're sober and you're going to church and you've
got a
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): family and thriving business and everything.
- The
Speaker 5: ride on mower racing and then stock car racing?
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): - Yeah, yeah. Yeah, that was the funnest ever. - You've had, like, just let's start with the ride on mowers. You've had mishaps, right? - Yeah. - What
happened? -
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): Crashed, got hurt a little
Man 24: bit, and just kept doing it. You know what I mean? You just make pretend it don't hurt. Yeah, I don't know
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): what happened. I mean, I got bum knee, bum arm, bum neck.
but
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): that's not just from
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): that that's i've i've crashed and smashed a lot on
a lot
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): of stuff like
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): what snowmobiles back when i used to drink yeah i wreck a snowmobile every winter just basically every
Man 24: winter and have to get another
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): one on on trees trees and
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): rocks and brooks a lot of people people in maine died so people die on snowmobiles yeah i can't believe i'm not one of those people
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): actually so now you race
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): at a big track in oxford maine well i used to i did it for two years yeah they got rid of the trucks this year they canned them no more trucks
Speaker 29: racing at oxford this year why i don't know but so
yeah
My
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): wife never really liked it So I'm just kind of going to back away from it You had a pretty bad crash though Yeah but it didn't hurt It was really cool I got out of the truck and
did a
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): bow And the crowd loved it What happened to your truck? Nothing I mean it dented Dented it But
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): broke some bent spindles And broke a few rims And smashed
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): a windshield But my stepdad
in
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): his garage with one leg fixed it in a week we raced the following week really yeah yeah while i worked yeah
the day i'd
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): go there in the evening he'd be pounding and smashing on to be all bloody knuckled
and got it ready and we
Speaker 80: did we
went we
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): raced again and the following week i did it again in practice and that
was
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): embarrassing that wasn't cool like the first time the second time was embarrassing what did you do the second
time
we were
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): in practice and a guy came underneath me and poked me
and i
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): spun sideways and
rolled like
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): four times did an endo and crashed you did an end
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): over end yeah i don't know i didn't see it but
Speaker 81: they told me they
told me if last
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): week's crash was an 8.5 this week's was a 10 that's what one guy told me so i was like all right yeah but it wasn't it was embarrassing
this
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): time it was embarrassing so
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): when you're in a vehicle on a track at high speed and it's going in over end or side over side what are
you thinking please
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): stop before i run into something
that's what i was
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): thinking the first time when i was barrel and i was barrel rolling down victory lane yeah
i was like ah it
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): was like
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): took forever you know what i mean and then when i came to stop I was on my roof, and
I'm
Speaker 75: like, oh, okay. So...
the lady
Speaker 75: come over she said you all right i'm like yeah yeah i'm fine so i
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): put my hand down i could smell gas i put my hand down it was all wet with gas so then i'm like trying to freak
Speaker 83: were you smoking no no
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): but i was
afraid you know one
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): little spark you know the truck's hot you've been racing oh yeah there's a chance of fire so i kind of got a little nerved up
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): And I couldn't get my belt undone
because I
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): was kind of tripping out a little bit. And finally when I got done, I went smash down on the roof. And I got out and I was all covered with gas, but there was no fire and it was all good. And I got out and I was a little discombobulated and I turned towards the
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): crowd and I did a bow and they just went nuts and they loved it. And it was awesome.
Speaker 84: - Was your wife there? - Nope,
I think
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): she wasn't. - So let
me just
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): ask you finally about Trump a little more specifically. - Okay.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): So I
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): asked you what you're mad about in America. And the second thing you said was they're, they're persecuting Trump on political grounds. What
do you like
Speaker 66 (lower-pitched voice): about Trump? He
tells it
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): how it is. He's pro-business and he's anti-swamp.
What do you mean anti-swamp? In
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): our government, there's a bunch of people that,
you know,
All
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): they do is keep making the
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): government bigger and bigger and bigger to give themselves jobs. They have a budget and they make sure they spend every penny of it so that they can get more. Instead of trying to save some money, because they're all worried that they won't get as much in the next year's budget. So they spend every dime, every year, all the time. And that's what happens to a
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): bureaucracy. Job one of a bureaucracy is to make itself bigger. And...
Trump
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): recognized that and he tried cleaning it out, tried making it work right, work like a decent
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): business and they, that's why
they hate him so
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): much. That's why the left hates Trump is because he was trying to make our business, our government honest and
work for the
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): people, beneficial to you and I, you know? Yep.
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): He
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): wanted to do that and he exposed the lies, you know what I mean? He exposed the corruption and that's why they're doing what they're doing to him.
Could you
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): imagine how successful his presidency had been if he hadn't
had all the pushback by Trump?
by
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): the left, by the powers that be, by the press.
Imagine what we could
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): have gotten done in the past, 'cause it would have been eight years. He would have got elected the second
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): time if it weren't for the press. - Yeah. - And that's another thing,
I lay
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): blame to them. There's no free press anymore. They're not, they used to be, they used to hold the politicians accountable. Now,
only if you're a
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): Republican, do you get held accountable.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): you're a democrat and you just ignore you you know make only talk about it's it's so oh drives
me up a
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): wall if trump was here what would you say to him i'd shake his hand i'd
ask him if he was
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): looking for any help and
then i
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): tell him he's got my vote in
the fall and
i wouldn't bother
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): making any suggestions on what i think he should do to win because i know he wouldn't listen
that's about it isaac cooper it was
Speaker 87: great to see you at
lunch
Speaker 90: yeah and i'm glad you came thank you thanks for having me i'm humbled well i'm humbled that you would come
Speaker 91: yeah it's uh you know once in a lifetime opportunity well
Speaker 92: thank you
thank you
Speaker 93: hey it's tucker carlson the internet is crowded with interesting things that don't really matter on tcn we attempt to bring you interesting things that actually do matter and
Speaker 94: a lot of them interviews long form and short videos documentaries you can find all of it on tucker carlson.com and we hope you will free speech is bigger than any one person or any one organism societies are defined by what they will not permit what we're watching is the total inversion of virtue